- ♥ Bengaluru, India
- **8892625123**
- □ dashavanthk@outlook.com
- * linkedin.com/in/dashavanthk
- github.com/dashavanthk
- adashavanthk.github.io

DASHAVANTH KODIHALLI

LEAD ENGINEER

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A CREATIVE AND DETAILED INDIVIDUAL WITH ABILITY TO DEVELOP EFFECTIVE AND EFFICIENT SOLUTIONS WITH ZERO TOLERANCE FOR ERRORS.

LOOKING TO JOIN A PROGRESSIVE TECH COMPANY WHERE MY TECHNICAL &LEADERSHIP SKILLS WILL BE FULLY HARNESSED.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm an experienced developer with a solid background in .net development stages, from initial analysis through design and execution.

I'm proficient in a asp.net/core. In addition to my technical skills, I'm a great communicator and collaborator. Ability to communicate well enables me to collaborate effectively with clients to identify objectives and requirements for applications.

EMPLOYMENT

2020 - PRESENT LEAD ENGINEER - FIDELITY INFORMATION SERVICES (FIS GLOBAL)

ROLE C# .NET MVC/API DEVELOPER

- + Do the requirement gathering, analyse and assist other developers
- + Doing spike research on data migration, and develop data transform & load scripts across billing systems
- + Integrate the ORMB API with .net pricing console
- + Develop PL-SQL Procs, views
- + Look after UAT/Load environments and configurations, work with server admins to keep the environment healthy, up & running
- + Leading offshore dev team

PROJECTS UNIFIED PRICING CONSOLE - Payment Billing System

- + Integrated system of multiple prod environments of vast variants
- + Console which mainly used for pricing management and logical manipulations
- + Uses ORMB system on Oracle DB as a Backend for data process and billing logic.
- + Uses sequential files & batch jobs, for scheduling uses mainframe Tivoli
- + Used DevExpress controls for UI data management with MVC 4.7
- + Develop API to communicate back office to UI console using .Net core 2.0
- + Worked along configuring IIS & web farm on public/non-public servers
- + Work with QA team o functional overview & work on bug fixes.
- + Provide ongoing support to Production/ Go-Live planning

2017 – 2020 SENIOR ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT – NTI DATA

ROLE C# .NET / CORE DEVELOPER

- + Co-ordinated in Initial Design, Estimations for new modules
- + Took ownership of 3-4 modules dev-ops cycle (designing to deployment)
- + Providing support to the team members and coordinating with the onshore business team understand the requirements

PROJECTS

INCIDENT NAVIGATOR - Analytics, Survey

- Uses configurable, natural language-based constructs to recognize key words in unstructured data, this automates clustering of common ticket types, resulting in actionable
- + Used Kendo UI for data collection and reporting/ analytics at frontend
- + Worked on Telerik Adhoc reporting, implemented the report saving functionality in Web Forms. SSIS package development to ETL

AUTOMATED PPT GERNERATION

- + Tool that can automatically generate the reports which helps account team efficiency by reducing the mundane tasks of creating PPT
- + Created using Telerik Reporting as self-hosted service, integrated as RESTful service with MVC application

DATA MASKING UTILITY

- + Add-On tool to customers, highly configurable, lightweight tool to mask their sensitive information before they load data into our system
- Developed the console masking library to mask the data at the ETL process, also the desktop utility at client side before transferring the data.
 Using Win Forms and WPF

MORE...

EDUCATION

2013 – 2017

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY - VTU

+ Major in Electronics and Communications

SKILLS

FULL STACK

+ BACK-END : ASP.NET MVC, Web API, ASP.NET Core

+ FRONT-END : JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, Kendo.JS, DevExpress

+ LANGUAGES : C#, Python

+ DATABASE : SQL (MSSQL, Azure SQL, Oracle), NoSQL (MongoDB)

+ REPORTING : Telerik Reporting, SSRS
+ CLOUD/OPS : MS Azure, IIS, Web Farm

+ SERVICES : WCF

+ **SPA FWK** : Angular, Blazor (C#)

AWARDS

2018 SPOT AWARD - Hard Work

2019 STAR PERFORMANCE AWARD - Teamwork